<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ns8:ExtractValidReferenceDataRespMsg xsi:schemaLocation="" xmlns:ns0="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/ReferenceDataExportBASServiceType/V2" xmlns:ns1="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/MessageHeaderType/V2" xmlns:ns2="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/RDEntityEntryListType/V2" xmlns:ns3="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/RDEntityType/V2" xmlns:ns4="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/RDEntryType/V2" xmlns:ns5="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/RDStatusType/V2" xmlns:ns6="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/RDValidityPeriodType/V2" xmlns:ns7="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/LsdListType/V2" xmlns:ns8="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessActivityService/CSRD2/IReferenceDataExportBAS/V2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
   <ns0:MessageHeader>
      <ns1:AddressingInformation>
         <ns1:messageID>a74bb721-e8e2-4b51-83ac-1ade91f8ce38</ns1:messageID>
         <ns1:relatesTo>cf263b62-628f-4841-a451-6ce6aad8d2ff</ns1:relatesTo>
      </ns1:AddressingInformation>
      <ns1:RequestInformation>
         <ns4:ExtractValidReferenceDataReqMsg xmlns:ns6="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/ExtractType/V2" xmlns:ns5="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/OperationType/V2" xmlns:ns8="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/ExportingEntitiesType/V2" xmlns:ns12="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/FilterRefType/V2" xmlns:ns10="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/RDEntityFilterPairType/V2" xmlns:ns16="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/LanguageDescriptionsType/V2" xmlns:ns15="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/SynchronisationExtractType/V2" xmlns:ns14="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/RetrieveType/V2" xmlns:ns2="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/ExportType/V2" xmlns:ns4="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessActivityService/CSRD2/IReferenceDataExportBAS/V2" xmlns:ns3="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/StatementsType/V2">
            <ns0:MessageHeader>
               <ns1:AddressingInformation>
                  <ns1:messageID>cf263b62-628f-4841-a451-6ce6aad8d2ff</ns1:messageID>
               </ns1:AddressingInformation>
            </ns0:MessageHeader>
            <ns0:ExportType>
               <ns2:Operation>
                  <ns5:Extract>
                     <ns6:SnapshotDate value="2025-12-24"/>
                     <ns6:ExportingEntities>
                        <ns8:RDView name="NCTS-P6"/>
                        <ns8:RDEntityList>
                           <ns8:RDEntity>
                              <ns10:RDEntityName name="XmlErrorCodes"/>
                           </ns8:RDEntity>
                        </ns8:RDEntityList>
                     </ns6:ExportingEntities>
                  </ns5:Extract>
               </ns2:Operation>
            </ns0:ExportType>
         </ns4:ExtractValidReferenceDataReqMsg>
      </ns1:RequestInformation>
   </ns0:MessageHeader>
   <ns0:RDEntityList>
      <ns2:RDEntity name="XmlErrorCodes">
         <ns3:RDEntry>
            <ns4:RDEntryStatus>
               <ns5:state>valid</ns5:state>
               <ns5:activeFrom>2025-11-01</ns5:activeFrom>
            </ns4:RDEntryStatus>
            <ns4:dataItem name="XmlErrorCodesCode">12</ns4:dataItem>
            <ns4:LsdList>
               <ns7:description lang="bg">Стойността на елемент в съобщението е извън предвидените стойности или не е част от приложимите технически кодове (стойността на елемента не е валидна по отношение на изброените). Този тип грешка е приложима за всички елементи, за които са предвидени кодове, както и за елементите, които идентифицират типа на съобщението.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="cs">Hodnota prvku ve zprávě je mimo předdefinovanou sadu hodnot nebo není součástí příslušného seznamu technických kódů (vzhledem k výčtu toto není platné). Tento typ chyby platí pro všechny prvky s kódovými hodnotami, takže je také použitelný pro ty prvky, které identifikují typ zprávy.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="da">Elementets værdi ligger udenfor det foruddefinerede værdisæt eller optræder ikke på den pågældende tekniske codelist.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="de">Wert eines Elements in einer Nachricht ist außerhalb des definierten Wertebereichs oder nicht Teil der gültigen technischen Codeliste. Dieser Fehlertyp gilt für alle Elemente mit Codierungen, so dass dieser auch für jene Elemente gilt, die einen Nachrichtentyp identifizieren.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="el">Η τιμή ενός στοιχείου σε ένα μήνυμα είναι εκτός του προκαθορισμένου συνόλου τιμών ή δεν αποτελεί μέρος του ισχύοντος τεχνικού καταλόγου κωδικών (δεν είναι έγκυρη ως προς την απαρίθμηση). Αυτός ο τύπος σφάλματος ισχύει για όλα τα στοιχεία με τιμές κώδικα, επομένως ισχύει επίσης για εκείνα τα στοιχεία που προσδιορίζουν έναν τύπο μηνύματος.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="en">Incorrect enumeration</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="es">Incorrect enumeration .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="et">Sõnumis sisalduv element on väljaspool eelmääratud väärtuste kogumit või see ei sisaldu kohalduvas tehniliste koodide loendis (see ei ole kehtiv nummerduse seisukohast). Seda liiki viga kehtib kõigi koodväärtustega elementide puhul, mistõttu kohaldub see ka sõnumi liiki tuvastavate elementide suhtes.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fi">Numerointi on väärin.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fr">Énumération incorrecte</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hr">Vrijednost podatka u poruci je izvan unaprijed određenog skupa vrijednosti ili nije dio primjenjive tehničke kodne liste (nije valjan za unos) . Ova vrsta greške je primjenjiva za sve podatke koji sadrže kodirane vrijednosti, također je primjenjiva za podatke koji identificiraju vrstu poruke</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hu">Egy elem értéke egy üzenetben az előre meghatározott értékkészleten kívül van vagy nem része az alkalmazható technikai kód listának (nem a számlálás szempontjából érvényes szempont). Ez a típusú hiba alkalmazható minden elemre kóde értékkel, így alkalmazható azokra az elemekre is, melyek azonosítanak egy üzenet típust.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="it">Il valore di un elemento nel messaggio non è compreso nel set predefinito di valori o non fa parte della lista dei codici applicabile (non è compreso nella lista dei codici validi). Questo tipo di errore è applicabile a tutti gli elementi codificati, perciò è applicabile anche a quegli elementi che identificano un tipo di messaggio</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lt">Neteisingas išvardijimas</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lv">Elementa vērtība ziņojumā pārsniedz iepriekš definēto vērtību kopumu vai nav daļa no piemērojamo tehnisko kodu saraksta (tās fasete nav derīga attiecībā uz uzskaitījumu). Šī veida kļūda attiecas uz visiem elementiem ar koda vērtībām, tādējādi tā attiecas arī uz tiem elementiem, kas identificē ziņojuma veidu.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="me">Neispravna enumeracija / Nevažeća vrijednost iz liste</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="mt">Incorrect enumeration .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="nl">Onjuiste opsomming</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pl">Wartość elementu jest spoza uprzednio zdefiniowanego zestawu wartości albo nie jest częścią mającej zastosowanie listy kodów technicznych. Ten rodzaj błędu stosuje się do wszystkich elementów z wartościami słownikowymi, w tym także do tych, które identyfikują rodzaj komunikatu.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pt">O valor de um elemento numa mensagem está fora do conjunto de valores predefinido ou não faz parte da lista de códigos técnicos aplicáveis (não é um aspecto válido em relação à enumeração). Este tipo de erro é aplicável a todos os elementos com valores de código, por isso também é aplicável a todos os elementos que identificam um tipo de mensagem.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="ro">Valoarea unui element dintr-un mesaj este în afara setului predefinit de valori sau nu face parte din lista codurilor tehnice aplicabile (nu este validă fațetă în ceea ce privește enumerarea). Acest tip de eroare este valabilă pentru toate elementele cu valori de cod, deci este aplicabilă și acelor elemente care identifică un tip de mesaj.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sk">Hodnota elementu v správe je mimo vopred definovaný súbor hodnôt alebo nie je súčasťou príslušného zoznamu technických kódov (nie je platná vo vzťahu k výpočtu). Tento typ chyby sa vzťahuje na všetky prvky s kódovými hodnotami, takže je tiež použiteľný na tie prvky, ktoré identifikujú typ správy.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sl">Vrednost elementa v sporočilu je zunaj vnaprej določenega niza vrednosti ali ni del veljavnega seznama tehničnih šifrantov (neveljavna vrednost glede na predpisano številčenje). Ta vrsta napake velja za vse elemente s kodnimi vrednostmi, zato se uporablja tudi za tiste elemente, ki označujejo vrsto sporočila.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sr">Netačno nabrajanje</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sv">Incorrect enumeration .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="uk">Некоректний перелік</ns7:description>
            </ns4:LsdList>
         </ns3:RDEntry>
         <ns3:RDEntry>
            <ns4:RDEntryStatus>
               <ns5:state>valid</ns5:state>
               <ns5:activeFrom>2025-11-01</ns5:activeFrom>
            </ns4:RDEntryStatus>
            <ns4:dataItem name="XmlErrorCodesCode">13</ns4:dataItem>
            <ns4:LsdList>
               <ns7:description lang="bg">Задължителни/изискуеми елементи липсват в получените данни, т.е. изисквани елементи не са представени.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="cs">V přijatých datech chybí povinný / požadovaný prvek, např. požadovaný prvek není přítomen</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="da">Et obligatorisk element mangler i de modtagne data.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="de">Ein obligatorisches Datenelment fehlt in den empfangenen Daten, z.B. ein Mussfeld ist nicht vorhanden</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="el">Ένα υποχρεωτικό / απαιτούμενο στοιχείο λείπει από τα ληφθέντα δεδομένα, π.χ. ένα απαιτούμενο στοιχείο δεν υπάρχει.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="en">Missing</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="es">Missing .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="et">Vastu võetud andmed ei sisalda kohustuslikku/nõutud elementi, st nõutud element puudub.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fi">Puuttuu.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fr">Valeur manquante</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hr">Missing .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hu">Egy kötelező/megkövetelt elem hiányzik a kapott adatból, például egy megkövetelt elem nincs jelen</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="it">Manca nei dati ricevuti un elemento obbligatorio/richiesto</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lt">Trūksta</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lv">Saņemtajos datos trūkst obligāta/vajadzīga elementa, piemēram, vajadzīgs elements nav klātesošs.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="me">Nedostaje / Nije unijeto</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="mt">Missing .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="nl">Ontbreekt</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pl">Wymagany/obowiązkowy element nie jest obecny</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pt">Falta um elemento obrigatório / requerido nos dados recebidos, p.ex. um elemento obrigatório não está presente.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="ro">Un element obligatoriu / cerut lipsește din datele primite, de ex. un element necesar nu este furnizat</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sk">V prijatých údajoch chýba povinný/požadovaný prvok, napr. požadovaný prvok nie je prítomný.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sl">V prejetih podatkih manjka obvezen/zahtevan element, npr. zahtevan element ni prisoten.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sr">Nedostaje</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sv">Missing .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="uk">Відсутній</ns7:description>
            </ns4:LsdList>
         </ns3:RDEntry>
         <ns3:RDEntry>
            <ns4:RDEntryStatus>
               <ns5:state>valid</ns5:state>
               <ns5:activeFrom>2025-11-01</ns5:activeFrom>
            </ns4:RDEntryStatus>
            <ns4:dataItem name="XmlErrorCodesCode">15</ns4:dataItem>
            <ns4:LsdList>
               <ns7:description lang="bg">Не се допуска елемента да има стойност, тъй като не е предвидено да присъства съгласно спецификацията на съобщенията (TMS) (включително и последователността на елементите).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="cs">Prvek nesmí mít hodnotu, protože není povoleno aby podle specifikace zprávy TMS (včetně sekvence prvků) byl přítomen.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="da">Et element er ikke tilladt at have en værdi fordi elementet jf. TMS message specifikationen ikke skal være der.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="de">Ein Datenelement darf keinen Wert enthalten weil dies nach den TMS Message Spezifikation nicht zugelassen ist</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="el">Ένα στοιχείο δεν επιτρέπεται να έχει μια τιμή επειδή δεν επιτρέπεται σύμφωνα με τις προδιαγραφές του μηνύματος (συμπεριλαμβανομένης της σειράς των στοιχείων).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="en">Not supported in this position</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="es">Not supported in this position .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="et">Element ei tohi omada väärtust, kuna see ei tohi sõnumis sisaldada TMS sõnumi spetsifikatsiooni (sh elementide järjestus) kohaselt.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fi">Ei mahdollinen tässä kohdassa.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fr">Non pris en charge pour cette position</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hr">Podatak nedozvoljeno sadrži vrijednost a isto nije dozboljeno sukladno TMS specifikaciji poruke (uključujući slijed podataka)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hu">Nem megengedett, hogy egy elemnek értéke legyen, mivel nem szabad jelen lennie a TMS üzenet specifikáció alapján (beleértve az elemek sorrendjét)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="it">Un elemento non può essere valorizzato perché non può essere presente secondo le specifiche del messaggio TSM (che include una sequenza di elementi)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lt">Nepalaikoma šioje pozicijoje</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lv">Elementam nedrīkst būt vērtība, jo elements nedrīkst būt klātesošs saskaņā ar TMS ziņojumu specifikāciju (ieskaitot elementu secību).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="me">Nije podržano na ovoj poziciji</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="mt">Not supported in this position .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="nl">Niet ondersteund in deze positie</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pl">Nie dopuszcza się by element posiadał wartość, ponieważ jego obecność jest niedopuszczalna zgodnie ze specyfikacją komunikatów TMS (włączając sekwencję elementów)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pt">Um elemento não pode ter um valor porque não lhe é permitido estar presente de acordo com a especificação da mensagem TMS (incluindo a sequência de elementos).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="ro">Un element nu poate avea o valoare deoarece nu este în conformitate cu specificația mesajului TMS (inclusiv secvența elementelor).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sk">Element nesmie mať hodnotu, pretože podľa špecifikácie správ TMS to nie je povolené (vrátane sekvencie prvkov).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sl">Elementu ni dovoljeno, da ima vrednosti, ker ni dovoljen v skladu s specifikacijami sporočila TMS (vključno z zaporedjem elementov).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sr">Nije podržano na ovoj poziciji</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sv">Not supported in this position .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="uk">Не підтримується на цій позиції</ns7:description>
            </ns4:LsdList>
         </ns3:RDEntry>
         <ns3:RDEntry>
            <ns4:RDEntryStatus>
               <ns5:state>valid</ns5:state>
               <ns5:activeFrom>2025-11-01</ns5:activeFrom>
            </ns4:RDEntryStatus>
            <ns4:dataItem name="XmlErrorCodesCode">18</ns4:dataItem>
            <ns4:LsdList>
               <ns7:description lang="bg">Непредвидена грешка</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="cs">Nespecifikovaná chyba</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="da">Uspecificeret fejl</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="de">Unspezifischer Fehler</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="el">Απροσδιόριστο σφάλμα</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="en">Unspecified Error / Other</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="es">Unspecified Error / Other .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="et">Täpsustamata viga</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fi">Määrittelemätön virhe.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fr">Erreur non spécifiée/Autre</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hr">Neodređena pogreška</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hu">Meghatározhatatlan hiba</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="it">Errore non specificato</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lt">Nenustatyta klaida / Kita</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lv">Nenorādīta kļūda</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="me">Nedefinisana greška / Drugo</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="mt">Unspecified Error / Other .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="nl">Niet gespecificeerd/ander</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pl">Nieokreślony błąd</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pt">Erro indeterminado</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="ro">Eroare nespecificată</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sk">Nešpecifikovaná chyba</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sl">Nedoločena napaka</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sr">Nedefinisana greška / Ostalo</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sv">Unspecified Error / Other .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="uk">Невизначена помилка / інше</ns7:description>
            </ns4:LsdList>
         </ns3:RDEntry>
         <ns3:RDEntry>
            <ns4:RDEntryStatus>
               <ns5:state>valid</ns5:state>
               <ns5:activeFrom>2025-11-01</ns5:activeFrom>
            </ns4:RDEntryStatus>
            <ns4:dataItem name="XmlErrorCodesCode">35</ns4:dataItem>
            <ns4:LsdList>
               <ns7:description lang="bg">Групата от данни се повтара повече отколкото е позволено</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="cs">Příliš mnoho opakování datové skupiny než je povoleno</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="da">Data gruppen indeholder flere individer end tilladt</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="de">Zu viele Wiederholungen einer Datengruppe als erlaubt</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="el">Πάρα πολλές επαναλήψεις μιας ομάδας δεδομένων σε σχέση με την επιτρεπόμενη</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="en">Too many repetitions</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="es">Too many repetitions .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="et">Andmegrupi korduseid liiga palju</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fi">Liian monta toistoa.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fr">Trop de répétitions</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hr">Previše ponavljanja grupe podataka od dozovljenog</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hu">Az adatcsoport túl sok ismétlődése, mint a megengedett</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="it">Ripetizioni dei data group in numero superiore al consentito</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lt">Per daug pasikartojimų</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lv">Datu grupas atkārtojumu ir vairāk, nekā atļauts</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="me">Previše ponavljanja</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="mt">Too many repetitions .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="nl">Te veel herhalingen</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pl">Więcej powtórzeń grupy danych niż dozwolono</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pt">Repetições de um grupo de dados para além das permitidas</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="ro">Prea multe repetări ale unui grup de date decât cele permise</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sk">Príliš veľa opakovaní dátovej skupiny ako je povolené</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sl">Več ponovitev podatkovne skupine od dovoljene</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sr">Previše ponavljanja</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sv">Too many repetitions .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="uk">Занадто багато повторень</ns7:description>
            </ns4:LsdList>
         </ns3:RDEntry>
         <ns3:RDEntry>
            <ns4:RDEntryStatus>
               <ns5:state>valid</ns5:state>
               <ns5:activeFrom>2025-11-01</ns5:activeFrom>
            </ns4:RDEntryStatus>
            <ns4:dataItem name="XmlErrorCodesCode">39</ns4:dataItem>
            <ns4:LsdList>
               <ns7:description lang="bg">Уведомление, че дължината на полученият елемент надвишава максималната дъллжина на определената в спецификацията.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="cs">Oznámení, že délka přijatého prvku překročila maximální zadanou délku.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="da">Længden af det indtastede er længere end tilladt</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="de">Mitteilung dass die Länge eines Datenelements die maximale Länge überschreitet</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="el">Ειδοποίηση ότι το μήκος ενός στοιχείου που παραλήφθηκε είναι μικρότερο από το καθορισμένο ελάχιστο μήκος.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="en">Element too long (length constraint)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="es">Element too long (length constraint) .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="et">Teavitus, et vastu võetud elemendi maksimaalne pikkus ületas määratud maksimaalse pikkuse.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fi">Elementti on liian pitkä (pituusrajoitus).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fr">Élément trop long (contrainte de longueur)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hr">Obavijest o duljini primljenog podatka prelazi maksimalnu navedenu duljinu</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hu">Értesítés, hogy a kapott elem hossza meghaladja meghatározott maximális hosszúságot</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="it">La lunghezza dell'elemento ricevuto eccede la lunghezza massima specificata</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lt">Elementas per ilgas (ilgio apribojimas)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lv">Paziņojums par to, ka saņemtā elementa garums ir pārsniedzis maksimālo norādīto garumu.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="me">Element je predugačak (ograničenje dužine)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="mt">Element too long (length constraint) .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="nl">Element te lang (lengtebeperking)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pl">Długość elementu przekracza długość maksymalną</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pt">Notificação de que o comprimento do elemento recebido excedeu o comprimento máximo especificado.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="ro">Notificarea că lungimea elementului primit depășește lungimea maximă specificată.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sk">Oznámenie, že dĺžka prijatého prvku presahuje stanovenú maximálnu určenú dĺžku.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sl">Obvestilo, da je dolžina prejetega elementa presegla najdaljšo določeno dolžino.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sr">Predugačak element (ograničenje dužine)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sv">Element too long (length constraint) .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="uk">Задовге значення (обмеження довжини)</ns7:description>
            </ns4:LsdList>
         </ns3:RDEntry>
         <ns3:RDEntry>
            <ns4:RDEntryStatus>
               <ns5:state>valid</ns5:state>
               <ns5:activeFrom>2025-11-01</ns5:activeFrom>
            </ns4:RDEntryStatus>
            <ns4:dataItem name="XmlErrorCodesCode">40</ns4:dataItem>
            <ns4:LsdList>
               <ns7:description lang="bg">Уведомление, че дължината на полученият елемент е по-малка от минималноопределената дължина в спецификацията</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="cs">Oznámení, že délka přijatého prvku je kratší než zadaná minimální délka.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="da">Længden af det indtastede er kortere end tilladt</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="de">Meldung, dass die Länge eines Datenelements die minimale Länge unterschreitet</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="el">Ειδοποίηση ότι το μήκος ενός στοιχείου που παραλήφθηκε είναι μικρότερο από το καθορισμένο ελάχιστο μήκος.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="en">Element too short (length constraint)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="es">Element too short (length constraint) .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="et">Teavitus, et vastu võetud element on lühem kui määratud minimaalne pikkus.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fi">Elementti on liian lyhyt (pituusrajoitus).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fr">Élément trop court (contrainte de longueur)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hr">Obavijest da je duljina primljenog podatka kraća od navedene minimalne duljine</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hu">Értesítés, hogy a kapott elem hossza rövidebb, mint a meghatározott minimális hosszúság</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="it">L'elemento ricevuto è più corto della lunghezza minima specificata</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lt">Elementas per trumpas (ilgio apribojimas)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lv">Paziņojums par to, ka saņemtā elementa garums ir īsāks par minimālo norādīto garumu.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="me">Element je prekratak (ograničenje dužine)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="mt">Element too short (length constraint) .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="nl">Element te kort (lengtebeperking)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pl">Długość elementu jest krótsza niż długość minimalna</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pt">Notificação de que o comprimento de um elemento recebido é menor do que o comprimento mínimo especificado.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="ro">Notificarea că lungimea unui element primit este mai mică decât lungimea minimă specificată.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sk">Oznámenie, že dĺžka prijatého prvku je kratšia než stanovená minimálna dĺžka.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sl">Obvestilo, da je dolžina prejetega elementa krajša od predpisane najmanjše dolžine.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sr">Prekretak element (ograničenje dužine)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sv">Element too short (length constraint) .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="uk">Закоротке значення (обмеження довжини)</ns7:description>
            </ns4:LsdList>
         </ns3:RDEntry>
         <ns3:RDEntry>
            <ns4:RDEntryStatus>
               <ns5:state>valid</ns5:state>
               <ns5:activeFrom>2025-11-01</ns5:activeFrom>
            </ns4:RDEntryStatus>
            <ns4:dataItem name="XmlErrorCodesCode">50</ns4:dataItem>
            <ns4:LsdList>
               <ns7:description lang="bg">Стойността на специфичния елемен не е валидна съгласно типа на този елемент. Например MRN не съответства на дадената в спецификацията конвенция.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="cs">Hodnota konkrétní položky dat je neplatná podle typu tohoto prvku. Například MRN neodpovídá specifikacím uvedeným v úmluvě.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="da">Værdien i feltet er forkert i forhold til felttypen.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="de">Der Wert dieses spezifischen Datenelements ist ungültig bezogen auf die Art des Datenelements. Zum Beispiel stimmen die MRN nicht mit den Spezifikationen des Übereinkommens überein</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="el">Η τιμή του συγκεκριμένου δεδομένου είναι άκυρη σύμφωνα με τον τύπο του στοιχείου. Για παράδειγμα, το MRN δεν συμμορφώνεται με τις προδιαγραφές που παρέχονται στη σύμβαση.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="en">Invalid Value for the specific type</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="es">Invalid Value for the specific type .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="et">Konkreetse andmeühiku väärtus on kehtetu. Näiteks MRN ei vasta konventsioonis esitatud spetsifikatsioonidele.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fi">Väärä arvo tälle tyypille.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fr">Valeur non valide pour le type spécifique</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hr">Vrijednost određene stavke podataka nije valjana prema vrsti tog elementa. Primjerice, MRN ne odgovara specifikacijama navednima u konvenciji.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hu">A különelges adatelem értéke érvénytelen ennek az elemnek a típusa szerint. Például MRN nem felel meg az Egyezményben megadott leírásnak.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="it">Il valore dello specifico data item è invalido in base alla tipologia di elemento. Per esempio MRN non conforme.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lt">Negaliojanti konkretaus tipo reikšmė</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lv">Konkrētā datu vienuma vērtība ir nederīga atbilstoši šī elementa veidam. Piemēram, MRN neatbilst konvencijā norādītajām specifikācijām.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="me">Neispravna vrijednost za određeni tip</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="mt">Invalid Value for the specific type .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="nl">Ongeldige waarde voor het specifieke type</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pl">Wartość elementu jest nieprawidłowa dla tego rodzaju elementu. Np. MRN nie spełnia wymagań zawartych w specyfikacji.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pt">O valor do item de dados específico é inválido de acordo com o tipo desse elemento. Por exemplo, NRM não está em conformidade com as especificações da convenção.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="ro">Valoarea elementului de date specific este nevalidă în funcție de tipul acestui element. De exemplu, MRN nu se conformează specificațiilor date în convenție.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sk">Hodnota špecifickej údajovej položky je neplatná vzhľadom na typ tohto prvku. Napríklad MRN nezodpovedá špecifikáciám uvedeným v dohovore.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sl">Vrednost posameznega podatkovnega elementa je neveljavna glede na vrsto tega elementa. Na primer, MRN ne ustreza specifikacijam iz konvencije.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sr">Nevažeća vrednost za datu vrstu</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sv">Invalid Value for the specific type .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="uk">Недійсне значення для певного типу</ns7:description>
            </ns4:LsdList>
         </ns3:RDEntry>
         <ns3:RDEntry>
            <ns4:RDEntryStatus>
               <ns5:state>valid</ns5:state>
               <ns5:activeFrom>2025-11-01</ns5:activeFrom>
            </ns4:RDEntryStatus>
            <ns4:dataItem name="XmlErrorCodesCode">51</ns4:dataItem>
            <ns4:LsdList>
               <ns7:description lang="bg">Стойността на специфичния елемент не е валидна съгласно определения модел за този конкретен тип.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="cs">Hodnota konkrétní datové položky je neplatná vzhledem k definovanému vzoru pro tento konkrétní typ.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="da">Indtastningen i feltet overholder ikke mønstret for denne felttype</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="de">Der Wert des spezifischen Datenelements ist hinsichtlich des festgelegten Musters für diese spezielle Art ungültig</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="el">Η αξία του συγκεκριμένου δεδομένου δεν είναι έγκυρη σε σχέση με το καθορισμένο πρότυπο για το συγκεκριμένο είδος</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="en">Invalid value according to the pattern</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="es">Invalid value according to the pattern .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="et">Konkreetse andmeühiku väärtus on kehtetu selle konkreetse liigi jaoks määratletud mustri osas.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fi">Rakenteesta poikkeava vääränlainen arvo.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fr">Valeur invalide selon le modèle</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hr">Vrijednost određene stavke podataka nije važeća u odnosu na predviđeni obrazac za ovu određenu vrstu</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hu">A különelges adatelem értéke érvénytelen az erre a különleges típusra meghatározott minta tekintetében</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="it">Il valore dello specifico data item è invalido in base al modello definito per questa specifica tipologia</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lt">Netinkama reikšmė pagal šabloną</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lv">Konkrētā datu vienuma vērtība ir nederīga attiecībā uz definēto struktūru šim konkrētajam veidam.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="me">Neispravna vrijednost prema zadatom obrascu</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="mt">Invalid value according to the pattern .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="nl">Ongeldige waarde voor het patroon</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pl">Wartość konkretnej danej jest nieprawidłowa w odniesieniu do zdefiniowanego schematu tego rodzaju danych.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pt">O valor do item de dados específico é inválido em relação ao padrão definido para este tipo específico.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="ro">Valoarea elementului de date specific este nevalidă în raport cu modelul definit pentru acest tip specific.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sk">Hodnota konkrétnej údajovej položky je neplatná vzhľadom na definovaný vzor pre tento konkrétny typ.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sl">Vrednost posameznega podatkovnega elementa ni veljavna glede na določeno strukturo za ta podatkovni element.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sr">Nevežeća vrednost prema obrascu</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sv">Invalid value according to the pattern .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="uk">Недійсне значення відповідно до шаблону</ns7:description>
            </ns4:LsdList>
         </ns3:RDEntry>
         <ns3:RDEntry>
            <ns4:RDEntryStatus>
               <ns5:state>valid</ns5:state>
               <ns5:activeFrom>2025-11-01</ns5:activeFrom>
            </ns4:RDEntryStatus>
            <ns4:dataItem name="XmlErrorCodesCode">52</ns4:dataItem>
            <ns4:LsdList>
               <ns7:description lang="bg">Не е затворен XML tag</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="cs">Neuzavřené značky XML</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="da">XML tags ikke afsluttet</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="de">Nicht geschlossene XML Tags</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="el">Με τερματισμένη XML ετικέτα</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="en">Invalid XML format</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="es">Invalid XML format .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="et">Sulgemata XML-sildid</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fi">Virheellinen XML- muoto.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fr">Format XML invalide</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hr">Neoznačene XML oznake</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hu">Nyitott XML címke</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="it">Tags XML non chiusi</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lt">Negaliojantis XML formatas</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lv">Neaizvērti XML tagi</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="me">Neispravan XML format</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="mt">Invalid XML format .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="nl">Ongeldig XML formaat</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pl">Nieprawidłowa składnia XML</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pt">Marcas XML abertas</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="ro">tag-uri XML neînchise</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sk">Neukončené znaky XML</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sl">Nezaprte oznake XML</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sr">Nevažeći XML format</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sv">Invalid XML format .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="uk">Недійсний формат XML</ns7:description>
            </ns4:LsdList>
         </ns3:RDEntry>
         <ns3:RDEntry>
            <ns4:RDEntryStatus>
               <ns5:state>valid</ns5:state>
               <ns5:activeFrom>2025-11-01</ns5:activeFrom>
            </ns4:RDEntryStatus>
            <ns4:dataItem name="XmlErrorCodesCode">53</ns4:dataItem>
            <ns4:LsdList>
               <ns7:description lang="bg">Един (или повече) символ (и) е (са) използван в конкретен елемент, не е (са) валиден (и) знак (знаци)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="cs">Jeden (nebo více) znak (ů) použitý v konkrétní položce není (jsou) platný znak (y).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="da">Et eller flere karakterer brugt i indtastningen er ikke valide karakterer</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="de">Eine oder mehrere Zeichen die in den spezifischen Elementen verwendet wurden sind nicht gültige Zeichen</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="el">Ένας ή περισσότεροι χαρακτήρες που χρησιμοποιούνται σε ένα συγκεκριμένο στοιχείο δεν είναι έγκυροι.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="en">Invalid character(s)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="es">Invalid character(s) .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="et">Vähemalt üks konkreetses ühikus kasutatud tähemärk ei ole kehtiv.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fi">Virheellinen merkki/merkit.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fr">Caractère(s) invalide(s)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hr">Jedan (ili više) znak(ova) upotrijebljenih u određenoj stavci nije (nisu) valjani</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hu">Egy (vagy több), egy különleges tételnél használt karakter nem érvényes karakter.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="it">Uno o più caratteri usati in uno specifico item è/sono carattere/i non validi</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lt">Negaliojantis simbolis (simboliai)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lv">Viena vai vairākas konkrētā vienumā lietotas rakstzīmes nav derīgas rakstzīmes.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="me">Neispravni znak(ovi) / Nedozvoljeni karakter(i)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="mt">Invalid character(s) .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="nl">Ongeldig(e) karakter(s)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pl">Jeden (lub więcej) znak(ów) użytych w elemencie jest nieprawidłowy</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pt">Um (ou mais) caracter(es) usado(s) num item específico é (são) carater(es) não válido(s).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="ro">Unul (sau mai multe) caractere utilizate într-un anumit element nu este (sunt) caracter (e) valabil (e).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sk">Jeden (alebo viac) znakov používaných v konkrétnej položke nie je (sú) platným znakom (znakmi).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sl">En (ali več) znak/ov, ki se uporabljajo v določenem elementu, ni (niso) veljavni znak.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sr">Nevežeći karakter/i</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sv">Invalid character(s) .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="uk">Недійсний(-і) символ(и)</ns7:description>
            </ns4:LsdList>
         </ns3:RDEntry>
         <ns3:RDEntry>
            <ns4:RDEntryStatus>
               <ns5:state>valid</ns5:state>
               <ns5:activeFrom>2025-11-01</ns5:activeFrom>
            </ns4:RDEntryStatus>
            <ns4:dataItem name="XmlErrorCodesCode">54</ns4:dataItem>
            <ns4:LsdList>
               <ns7:description lang="bg">Стойността на елемента е по-малка от определената за този елемент най-малка стойност. Например, ако минималната дефинирана стойност е 99, тогава всяка стойност, по-ниска от тази, ще бъде невалидна (например 98).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="cs">Hodnota prvku je číselně nižší než nejnižší limit definovaný pro tuto datovou položku. Například pokud je minimální definovaná hodnota 99, pak jakákoli nižší hodnota pro tento limit bude neplatná (např. 98).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="da">Værdien i feltet er numerisk lavere end tilladt for dette felt. Hvis minimum tilladte værdi er 99 vil alle værdier under denne være forkert.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="de">Der Wert des Datenelements ist numerisch niedriger als der definierte niedrigste Wert. Zum Beispiel wenn der Mindestwert 99 ist, sind alle niedrigeren Werte üngültig (z.B. 89)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="el">Η τιμή του στοιχείου είναι αριθμητικά χαμηλότερη από το χαμηλότερο όριο που έχει οριστεί για αυτό το δεδομένο. Για παράδειγμα, αν η ελάχιστη καθορισμένη τιμή είναι 99, τότε οποιαδήποτε τιμή χαμηλότερη σε αυτό το όριο θα είναι άκυρη (π.χ. 98).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="en">Value is lower than the allowed lowest limit (Minimum Inclusive)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="es">Value is lower than the allowed lowest limit (Minimum Inclusive) .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="et">Elemendi väärtus on väiksem selle andmeühiku jaoks määratud madalaimast piirist. Näiteks kui minimaalne määratud väärtus on 99, siis igasugune elemendi väärtus alla selle on vigane (nt 98).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fi">Arvo on pienempi kuin sallittu alin määrä (minimiarvo mukaan lukien)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fr">La valeur est inférieure à la limite la plus basse autorisée (minimum inclus)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hr">Vrijednost ovog podatka je brojčano niža od donje granice određene za ovu stavku. Primjerice, ako je minimalna vrijednost 99 svaka vrijednost ispod ograničenja biti će nevažeća (npr. 98)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hu">Az elem értéke számszerűen alacsonyabb, mint az ezen adatelemhez meghatározott legalacsonyabb határérték. Például, ha a meghatározott minimális értéke 99, akkor bármely érték, ami alacsonyabb annál a határértéknél, érvénytelen lesz (pl.:98)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="it">Il valore dell'elemento è inferiore al limite minimo definito. Ad esempio, se il minimo valore definito è 99, ogni valore inferiore a quel limite non sarà valido (es. 98)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lt">Reikšmė yra mažesnė už leistiną žemiausią ribą (įskaitant minimalią)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lv">Elementa vērtība ir skaitliski mazāka nekā zemākā vērtība, kas definēta šim datu vienumam. Piemēram, ja minimālā definētā vērtība ir 99, tad jebkura par šo robežu mazāka vērtība (piemēram, 98) ir nederīga.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="me">Vrijednost je manja od dozvoljene minimalne granice (uključujući minimum)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="mt">Value is lower than the allowed lowest limit (Minimum Inclusive) .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="nl">Waarde is kleiner dan de toegestane limiet (inclusief minimale waarde)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pl">Wartość elementu jest numerycznie niższa niż dolny limit (np. dla min=99, wartości mniejsze są od 99 są neprawidłowe)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pt">O valor do elemento é numericamente inferior ao limite mais baixo definido para este item. Por exemplo, se o valor mínimo definido for 99, qualquer valor menor a esse limite será inválido (por exemplo, 98).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="ro">Valoarea elementului este numeric mai mică decât cea mai mică limită definită pentru acest element de date. De exemplu, dacă valoarea minimă definită este 99, atunci orice valoare inferioară acestei limite va fi nevalidă (de exemplu, 98).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sk">Hodnota prvku je číselne nižšia ako najnižšia hranica definovaná pre túto údajovú položku. Napríklad, ak je minimálna definovaná hodnota 99, potom každá hodnota nižšia pre tento limit bude neplatná (napr. 98).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sl">Vrednost elementa je številčno nižja od najnižje meje, določene za to podatkovno postavko. Če je na primer najnižja določena vrednost 99, je vsaka vrednost, nižja od te omejitve, neveljavna (npr. 98).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sr">Vrednost je niža od dozvoljene najniže granice (uključujući minimum)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sv">Value is lower than the allowed lowest limit (Minimum Inclusive) .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="uk">Значення нижче за дозволену найнижчу межу (мінімум включно)</ns7:description>
            </ns4:LsdList>
         </ns3:RDEntry>
         <ns3:RDEntry>
            <ns4:RDEntryStatus>
               <ns5:state>valid</ns5:state>
               <ns5:activeFrom>2025-11-01</ns5:activeFrom>
            </ns4:RDEntryStatus>
            <ns4:dataItem name="XmlErrorCodesCode">55</ns4:dataItem>
            <ns4:LsdList>
               <ns7:description lang="bg">Стойността на елемента е по-голяма от определената за този елемент най-голяма стойност. Например, ако максимално дефинирана стойност е 100, тогава всяка стойност по-голяма от тази, ще бъде невалидна (например 101).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="cs">Hodnota prvku je číselně větší než horní hranice definovaná pro tuto datovou položku. Například pokud je maximální definovaná hodnota 100, pak jakákoli hodnota větší než tento limit bude neplatná (např. 101).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="da">Værdien i feltet er numerisk højere end tilladt for dette felt. Hvis maximum tilladte værdi er 100 vil alle værdier over denne være forkert.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="de">Der Wert des Datenelements ist numerisch größer als der höchste definierte Wert. Zum Beispiel wenn der maximale Wert bei 100 liegt, sind alle größeren Werte ungültig (z.B. 101).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="el">Η τιμή του στοιχείου είναι αριθμητικά μεγαλύτερη από το ανώτατο όριο που ορίζεται για αυτό το δεδομένο. Για παράδειγμα, εάν η μέγιστη καθορισμένη τιμή είναι 100, τότε οποιαδήποτε τιμή μεγαλύτερη από αυτό το όριο θα είναι άκυρη (π.χ. 101).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="en">Value is greater than the allowed upper limit (Maximum Inclusive)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="es">Value is greater than the allowed upper limit (Maximum Inclusive) .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="et">Elemendi väärtus on suurem selle andmeühiku jaoks määratud suurimast piirist. Näiteks kui maksimaalne määratud väärtus on 100, siis igasugune elemendi väärtus üle selle on vigane (nt 101).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fi">Arvo on suurempi kuin sallittu ylin määrä (maksimiarvo mukaan lukien)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fr">La valeur est supérieure à la limite supérieure autorisée (Maximum inclus)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hr">Vrijednost ovog podatka je brojčano veća od gornje granice određene za ovu stavku. Primjerice, ako je maksimalna vrijednost 100 svaka vrijednost veća od ograničenja biti će nevažeća (npr.101)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hu">Az elem értéke számszerűen magasabb, mint az ezen adatelemhez meghatározott legmagasabb határérték. Például, ha a meghatározott maximális érték 100, akkor bármlye érték, ami magasabb lesz a határértéknél, érvénytelen lesz (pl.:101)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="it">Il valore dell'elemento è superiore al limite massimo definito. Ad esempio, se il massimo valore definito è 100, ogni valore superiore a quel limite non sarà valido (es. 101)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lt">Reikšmė yra didesnė už leistiną aukščiausią ribą (įskaitant maksimalią)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lv">Elementa vērtība ir skaitliski lielāka nekā augstākā vērtība, kas definēta šim datu vienumam. Piemēram, ja maksimālā definētā vērtība ir 100, tad jebkura par šo robežu lielāka vērtība (piemēram, 101) ir nederīga.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="me">Vrijednost je veća od dozvoljene maksimalne granice (uključujući maksimum)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="mt">Value is greater than the allowed upper limit (Maximum Inclusive) .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="nl">Waarde is groter dan de toegestane limiet (inclusief maximale waarde)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pl">Wartość elementu jest numerycznie większa niż górny limit (np. dla max=100, wartości większe są nieprawidłowe).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pt">O valor do elemento é numericamente maior do que o limite superior definido para este item. Por exemplo, se o valor máximo definido for 100, qualquer valor maior para esse limite será inválido (por exemplo, 101).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="ro">Valoarea elementului este numeric mai mare decât limita superioară definită pentru acest element de date. De exemplu, dacă valoarea maximă definită este 100, atunci orice valoare mai mare pentru această limită va fi nevalidă (de exemplu, 101).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sk">Hodnota prvku je číselne väčšia ako horná hranica definovaná pre túto údajovú položku. Napríklad, ak je maximálna definovaná hodnota 100, potom každá hodnota väčšia ako tento limit bude neplatná (napr. 101).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sl">Vrednost elementa je večja od zgornje meje, določene za to podatkovno postavko. Če je na primer največja določena vrednost 100, je vsaka vrednost, ki je večja od te omejitve, neveljavna (npr. 101).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sr">Vrednost je veća od dozvoljene gornje granice (uključujući maksimum)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sv">Value is greater than the allowed upper limit (Maximum Inclusive) .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="uk">Значення перевищує дозволену верхню межу (максимум включно)</ns7:description>
            </ns4:LsdList>
         </ns3:RDEntry>
         <ns3:RDEntry>
            <ns4:RDEntryStatus>
               <ns5:state>valid</ns5:state>
               <ns5:activeFrom>2025-11-01</ns5:activeFrom>
            </ns4:RDEntryStatus>
            <ns4:dataItem name="XmlErrorCodesCode">56</ns4:dataItem>
            <ns4:LsdList>
               <ns7:description lang="bg">Стойността на елемента е по-малка от или равна на определената за този елемент най-малка стойност. Например, ако минималната дефинирана стойност е 99, тогава всяка стойност равна или по-ниска от тази, ще бъде невалидна (например 99).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="cs">Hodnota prvku je číselně nižší nebo rovna nejnižšímu limitu definovanému pro tuto datovou položku. Pokud je například minimální definovaná hodnota 99, pak jakákoli hodnota rovnající se nebo nižší než tento limit bude neplatná (např. 99).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="da">Værdien i feltet er numerisk lavere end eller lig med det tilladt for dette felt. Hvis minimum tilladte værdi er 99 vil alle værdier lig med eller under denne være forkert.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="de">Der Wert des Datenelements ist numerisch niedriger oder gleich dem definierten niedrisgsten Wert. Zum Beispiel wenn der Mindestwert 99 ist, sind alle Werte gleich oder niedriger üngültig (z.B. 99)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="el">Η τιμή του στοιχείου είναι αριθμητικά μικρότερη ή ίση με το κατώτατο όριο που ορίζεται για αυτό το δεδομένο. Για παράδειγμα, εάν η ελάχιστη καθορισμένη τιμή είναι 99, τότε οποιαδήποτε τιμή ίση ή χαμηλότερη από αυτό το όριο θα είναι άκυρη (π.χ. 99).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="en">Value is lower than or equal to the allowed lowest limit (Minimum Exclusive)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="es">Value is lower than or equal to the allowed lowest limit (Minimum Exclusive) .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="et">Elemendi väärtus on väiksem või võrdne selle andmeühiku jaoks määratud madalaimast piirist. Näiteks kui minimaalne määratud väärtus on 99, siis igasugune väiksem või võrdne elemendi väärtus on vigane (nt 99).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fi">Arvo on pienempi tai yhtä suuri kuin pienin sallittu määrä (minimiarvo ei sallittu)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fr">La valeur est inférieure ou égale à la limite la plus basse autorisée (minimum exclusif)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hr">Vrijednost ovog podatka je brojčano niža ili jednaka donjoj granici određenoj za ovu stavku. Primjerice, ako je minimalna vrijednost 99 svaka vrijednost ispod ograničenja biti će nevažeća (npr. 99)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hu">Az elem értéke számszerűen alacsonyabb, vagy egyenlő az ezen adatelemhez meghatározott legalacsonyabb határértékkel. Például, ha a meghatározott minimális értéke 99, akkor bármely érték, ami alacsonyabb, vagy egyenlől a határértékkel, érvénytelen lesz (pl.:99)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="it">Il valore dell'elemento è inferiore o uguale al limite minimo definito. Ad esempio, se il minimo valore definito è 99, ogni valore inferiore o uguale a quel limite non sarà valido (es. 99)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lt">Reikšmė yra mažesnė už leistiną žemiausią ribą (neįskaitant minimalios)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lv">Elementa vērtība ir skaitliski mazāka nekā zemākā vērtība, kas definēta šim datu vienumam, vai vienāda ar to. Piemēram, ja minimālā definētā vērtība ir 99, tad jebkura vērtība, kas ir vienāda ar šo robežu vai mazāka par to (piemēram, 99), ir nederīga.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="me">Vrijednost je manja ili jednaka dozvoljenoj minimalnoj granici (isključujući minimum)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="mt">Value is lower than or equal to the allowed lowest limit (Minimum Exclusive) .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="nl">Waarde is kleiner of gelijk aan de toegestane waarde (exclusief minimale waarde)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pl">Wartość elementu jest numerycznie niższa niż lub równa dolnemu limitowi (np. dla min=99, wartości 99, 98 itd są nieprwidłowe).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pt">O valor do elemento é numericamente inferior ou igual ao limite mais baixo definido para este item. Por exemplo, se o valor mínimo definido for 99, qualquer valor igual ou inferior a esse limite será inválido (por exemplo, 99).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="ro">Valoarea elementului este numeric mai mică sau egală cu cea mai mică limită definită pentru acest element de date. De exemplu, dacă valoarea minimă definită este 99, atunci orice valoare egală sau mai mică cu această limită va fi nevalidă (de ex., 99).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sk">Hodnota prvku je číselne nižšia alebo rovná najnižšiemu limitu definovanému pre túto údajovú položku. Ak je napríklad minimálna definovaná hodnota 99, potom každá hodnota rovnajúca sa alebo nižšia ako tento limit bude neplatná (napríklad 99).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sl">Vrednost elementa je številčno nižja ali enaka najnižji meji, določeni za to podatkovno postavko. Če je na primer najnižja določena vrednost 99, je vsaka vrednost, ki je enaka ali nižja od te omejitve, neveljavna (npr. 99)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sr">Vrednost je niža od ili jednaka dozvoljenoj najnižoj granici (isključujući minimun)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sv">Value is lower than or equal to the allowed lowest limit (Minimum Exclusive) .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="uk">Значення нижче або дорівнює дозволеній нижній межі (мінімальне виняткове значення)</ns7:description>
            </ns4:LsdList>
         </ns3:RDEntry>
         <ns3:RDEntry>
            <ns4:RDEntryStatus>
               <ns5:state>valid</ns5:state>
               <ns5:activeFrom>2025-11-01</ns5:activeFrom>
            </ns4:RDEntryStatus>
            <ns4:dataItem name="XmlErrorCodesCode">57</ns4:dataItem>
            <ns4:LsdList>
               <ns7:description lang="bg">Стойността на елемента е по-голяма от или равна на определената за този елемент най-голяма стойност. Например, ако максимално дефинирана стойност е 100, тогава всяка стойност по-голяма от или равна на тази, ще бъде невалидна (например 100).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="cs">Hodnota prvku je číselně větší nebo rovna horní hranici definované pro tuto datovou položku. Například pokud je maximální definovaná hodnota 100, pak jakákoli hodnota větší než tento limit bude neplatná (např. 100).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="da">Værdien i feltet er numerisk højere end eller lig med det tilladte for dette felt. Hvis maximum tilladte værdi er 100 vil alle værdier lig med eller over denne være forkert.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="de">Der Wert des Datenelements ist numerisch größer oder gleich dem definierten höchstem Wert. Zum Beispiel wenn der Maximumwert 100 ist, sind alle Werte gleich oder größer üngültig (z.B. 100)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="el">Η τιμή του στοιχείου είναι αριθμητικά μεγαλύτερη ή ίση με το ανώτερο όριο που ορίζεται για αυτό το δεδομένο. Για παράδειγμα, εάν η μέγιστη καθορισμένη τιμή είναι 100, τότε οποιαδήποτε τιμή μεγαλύτερη από αυτό το όριο θα είναι άκυρη (π.χ. 100).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="en">Value is greater than or equal to the allowed upper limit (Maximum Exclusive)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="es">Value is greater than or equal to the allowed upper limit (Maximum Exclusive) .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="et">Elemendi väärtus on suurem või võrdne selle andmeühiku jaoks määratud suurimast piirist. Näiteks kui maksimaalne määratud väärtus on 100, siis igasugune võrdne või suurem elemendi väärtus on vigane (nt 100).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fi">Arvo on suurempi tai yhtä suuri kuin suurin sallittu määrä (maksimiarvo ei sallittu).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fr">La valeur est supérieure ou égale à la limite supérieure autorisée (Maximum exclusif)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hr">Vrijednost ovog podatka je brojčano veća ili jednaka gornjoj granici određenoj za ovu stavku. Primjerice, ako je maksimalna vrijednost 100 svaka vrijednost veća od ograničenja biti će nevažeća (npr.100)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hu">Az elem értéke számszerűen magasabb, vagy egyenlő az ezen adatelemhez meghatározott legmagasabb határértékkel. Például, ha a meghatározott maximális érték 100, akkor bármlye érték, ami magasabb, vagy egyenlő lesz a határértékkel, érvénytelen lesz (pl.:100)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="it">Il valore dell'elemento è superiore o uguale al limite massimo definito. Ad esempio, se il massimo valore definito è 100, ogni valore superiore o uguale a quel limite non sarà valido (es. 100)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lt">Reikšmė yra didesnė už leistiną aukščiausią ribą (neįskaitant maksimalios)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lv">Elementa vērtība ir skaitliski lielāka nekā augstākā vērtība, kas definēta šim datu vienumam, vai vienāda ar to. Piemēram, ja maksimālā definētā vērtība ir 100, tad jebkura par šo robežu lielāka vērtība (piemēram, 100) ir nederīga.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="me">Vrijednost je veća ili jednaka dozvoljenoj maksimalnoj granici (isključujući maksimum)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="mt">Value is greater than or equal to the allowed upper limit (Maximum Exclusive) .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="nl">Waarde is groter of gelijk aan de toegestane waarde (exclusief maximale waarde)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pl">Wartość elementu jest numerycznie większa niż lub równa górnemu limitowi (np. dla max=100, wartości 100, 101, itd są nieprawidłowe).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pt">O valor do elemento é numericamente maior ou igual ao limite superior definido para este item. Por exemplo, se o valor máximo definido for 100, qualquer valor maior para esse limite será inválido (por exemplo, 100).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="ro">Valoarea elementului este numeric mai mare sau egală cu limita superioară definită pentru acest element de date. De exemplu, dacă valoarea maximă definită este 100, atunci orice valoare mai mare pentru această limită va fi nevalidă (de exemplu, 100).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sk">Hodnota prvku je číselne väčšia alebo rovná hornej hranici definovanej pre túto údajovú položku. Napríklad, ak je maximálna definovaná hodnota 100, potom je akákoľvek hodnota väčšia tomuto limitu neplatná (napr. 100).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sl">Vrednost elementa je večja ali enaka zgornji meji, ki je določena za to podatkovno postavko. Na primer, če je najvišja določena vrednost 100, je vsaka vrednost, ki je večja od te omejitve, neveljavna (npr. 100).</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sr">Vrednost je veća ili jednaka dozvoljenog gornjoj granici (isključujući maksimum)</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sv">Value is greater than or equal to the allowed upper limit (Maximum Exclusive) .{en}.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="uk">Значення більше або дорівнює дозволеній верхній межі (максимальне виняткове значення)</ns7:description>
            </ns4:LsdList>
         </ns3:RDEntry>
      </ns2:RDEntity>
   </ns0:RDEntityList>
</ns8:ExtractValidReferenceDataRespMsg>
