<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ns8:ExtractValidReferenceDataRespMsg xsi:schemaLocation="" xmlns:ns0="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/ReferenceDataExportBASServiceType/V2" xmlns:ns1="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/MessageHeaderType/V2" xmlns:ns2="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/RDEntityEntryListType/V2" xmlns:ns3="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/RDEntityType/V2" xmlns:ns4="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/RDEntryType/V2" xmlns:ns5="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/RDStatusType/V2" xmlns:ns6="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/RDValidityPeriodType/V2" xmlns:ns7="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/LsdListType/V2" xmlns:ns8="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessActivityService/CSRD2/IReferenceDataExportBAS/V2" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
   <ns0:MessageHeader>
      <ns1:AddressingInformation>
         <ns1:messageID>6a5004f3-abdf-4e51-9895-562e6a635d05</ns1:messageID>
         <ns1:relatesTo>bd02d621-4b7e-41a0-b083-a88a46c399a1</ns1:relatesTo>
      </ns1:AddressingInformation>
      <ns1:RequestInformation>
         <ns4:ExtractValidReferenceDataReqMsg xmlns:ns6="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/ExtractType/V2" xmlns:ns5="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/OperationType/V2" xmlns:ns8="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/ExportingEntitiesType/V2" xmlns:ns12="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/FilterRefType/V2" xmlns:ns10="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/RDEntityFilterPairType/V2" xmlns:ns16="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/LanguageDescriptionsType/V2" xmlns:ns15="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/SynchronisationExtractType/V2" xmlns:ns14="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/RetrieveType/V2" xmlns:ns2="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/ExportType/V2" xmlns:ns4="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessActivityService/CSRD2/IReferenceDataExportBAS/V2" xmlns:ns3="http://xmlns.ec.eu/BusinessObjects/CSRD2/StatementsType/V2">
            <ns0:MessageHeader>
               <ns1:AddressingInformation>
                  <ns1:messageID>bd02d621-4b7e-41a0-b083-a88a46c399a1</ns1:messageID>
               </ns1:AddressingInformation>
            </ns0:MessageHeader>
            <ns0:ExportType>
               <ns2:Operation>
                  <ns5:Extract>
                     <ns6:SnapshotDate value="2025-12-24"/>
                     <ns6:ExportingEntities>
                        <ns8:RDView name="NCTS-P6"/>
                        <ns8:RDEntityList>
                           <ns8:RDEntity>
                              <ns10:RDEntityName name="IncidentCode"/>
                           </ns8:RDEntity>
                        </ns8:RDEntityList>
                     </ns6:ExportingEntities>
                  </ns5:Extract>
               </ns2:Operation>
            </ns0:ExportType>
         </ns4:ExtractValidReferenceDataReqMsg>
      </ns1:RequestInformation>
   </ns0:MessageHeader>
   <ns0:RDEntityList>
      <ns2:RDEntity name="IncidentCode">
         <ns3:RDEntry>
            <ns4:RDEntryStatus>
               <ns5:state>valid</ns5:state>
               <ns5:activeFrom>2025-11-01</ns5:activeFrom>
            </ns4:RDEntryStatus>
            <ns4:dataItem name="Code">1</ns4:dataItem>
            <ns4:LsdList>
               <ns7:description lang="bg">превозвачът трябва да се отклони от предписания маршрут по член 298 от настоящия регламент поради обстоятелства извън неговия контрол;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="cs">dopravce je nucen odchýlit se od trasy stanovené v souladu s článkem 298 tohoto nařízení v důsledku okolností, které nemohl ovlivnit;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="da">transportøren er nødsaget til at afvige fra den rute, der er angivet i henhold til denne forordnings artikel 298, på grund af omstændigheder, som han ikke er herre over</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="de">der Beförderer aus von ihm nicht zu vertretenden Gründen gezwungen ist, von der verbindlichen Beförderungsroute gemäß Artikel 298 abzuweichen;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="el">είναι υποχρεωμένος να παρεκκλίνει από τη διαδρομή που έχει καθοριστεί σύμφωνα με το άρθρο 298 του παρόντος κανονισμού λόγω περιστάσεων που εκφεύγουν από τον έλεγχό του·</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="en">The carrier is obliged to deviate from the itinerary prescribed in accordance with Article 298 of UCC/IA Regulation due to circumstances beyond the carrier's control.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="es">cuando el transportista se vea obligado a desviarse del itinerario obligatorio fijado de conformidad con el artículo 298 del presente Reglamento debido a circunstancias ajenas a su voluntad;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="et">Vedaja on temast mitteolenevatel põhjustel sunnitud kalduma kõrvale vastavalt RA artiklile 298 kindlaksmääratud marsruudist.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fi">liikenteenharjoittajan on pakko poiketa tämän asetuksen 298 artiklan mukaisesti vahvistetusta kulkureitistä liikenteenharjoittajasta riippumattomien olosuhteiden vuoksi;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fr">Le transporteur est obligé de s’écarter de l’itinéraire prescrit conformément à l’article 298 du présent règlement en raison de circonstances indépendantes de sa volonté.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hr">ako je prijevoznik obvezan skrenuti s puta utvrđenog u skladu s člankom 298. ove Uredbe zbog okolnosti koje su izvan njegove kontrole;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hu">a fuvarozó rajta kívül álló körülmények miatt kénytelen eltérni az e rendelet 298. cikkével összhangban előírt útvonaltól;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="it">il trasportatore è obbligato a deviare dall’itinerario fissato conformemente all’articolo 298 del presente regolamento per circostanze che sfuggono al suo controllo;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lt">Vežėjas dėl jam nepavaldžių aplinkybių privalo nukrypti nuo jam pagal Komisijos įgyvendinimo reglamento (ES) 2015/2447 298 straipsnį nustatyto maršruto.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lv">Pārvadātājam jānovirzās no maršruta, kas noteikts saskaņā ar Komisijas īstenošanas regulas (IA) 2015/2447 298. pantu, tādu apstākļu dēļ, kuri ir ārpus tā kontroles</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="me">Prevoznik je dužan da odstupi od propisane rute u skladu sa članom 298 UCC/IA propisa zbog okolnosti koje su van njegove kontrole.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="mt">it-trasportatur ikun obbligat li jiddevja mill-itinerarju preskritt skont l-Artikolu 298 ta’ dan ir-Regolament minħabba ċirkostanzi lil hinn mill-kontroll tiegħu;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="nl">de vervoerder door omstandigheden buiten zijn wil genoodzaakt is geweest om af te wijken van de voorgeschreven route in overeenstemming met artikel 298 van deze verordening;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pl">Przewoźnik jest zmuszony do zmiany trasy wyznaczonej zgodnie z art. 298 UKC/RW z powodu okoliczności od niego niezależnych.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pt">O transportador é obrigado a desviar-se do itinerário previsto em conformidade com o artigo 298.o do presente regulamento devido a circunstâncias alheias ao seu controlo;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="ro">transportatorul este obligat să devieze de la itinerarul prevăzut în conformitate cu articolul 298 din prezentul regulament din cauze independente de voința sa;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sk">Dopravca sa musí odkloniť od trasy predpísanej v súlade s článkom 298 VNCKÚ 2015/2447 z dôvodu okolností, ktoré sú mimo jeho kontroly.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sl">mora prevoznik odstopiti od načrta poti, predpisanega v skladu s členom 298 te uredbe zaradi okoliščin, na katere ni mogel vplivati;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sr">Prevoznik je primoran da odstupi od propisanog plana puta, u skladu sa članom 298. UCC/IA (član 321. Uredbe) usled okolnosti van njegove kontrole.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sv">Fraktföraren tvingas avvika från den enligt artikel 298 i denna förordning föreskrivna färdvägen till följd av omständigheter utanför dennes kontroll.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="uk">Перевізник зобов’язаний відхилитися від маршруту, встановленого відповідно до статті 298 Регламенту UCC/IA, через обставини, які не залежать від нього.</ns7:description>
            </ns4:LsdList>
         </ns3:RDEntry>
         <ns3:RDEntry>
            <ns4:RDEntryStatus>
               <ns5:state>valid</ns5:state>
               <ns5:activeFrom>2025-11-01</ns5:activeFrom>
            </ns4:RDEntryStatus>
            <ns4:dataItem name="Code">2</ns4:dataItem>
            <ns4:LsdList>
               <ns7:description lang="bg">пломбите са счупени или манипулирани по време на операцията по превоза по причини извън контрола на превозвача;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="cs">závěry jsou během tranzitní operace poškozeny nebo s nimi bylo neoprávněně manipulováno z důvodů, které nemohl dopravce ovlivnit;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="da">seglene er blevet brudt eller manipuleret under transporten, uden at dette kan tilskrives transportøren</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="de">Verschlüsse während der Beförderung aus vom Beförderer nicht zu vertretenden Gründen verletzt oder manipuliert werden;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="el">σε περίπτωση ρήξης ή παραποίησης των σφραγίδων κατά τη διάρκεια της μεταφοράς για λόγους ανεξάρτητους της θέλησης του μεταφορέα·</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="en">Seals are broken or tampered within the course of a transport operation for reasons beyond the carrier's control.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="es">cuando, durante el transporte, los precintos se rompan o sean objeto de manipulación por causas ajenas a la voluntad del transportista;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="et">Veo jooksul on tollitõkendid vedajast mitteolenevatel põhjustel lõhutud või rikutud.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fi">sinetit ovat rikkoutuneet tai niihin on kajottu kuljetuksen aikana liikenteenharjoittajasta riippumattomista syistä;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fr">Les scellés sont brisés ou manipulés irrégulièrement au cours d’une opération de transport pour des raisons indépendantes de la volonté du transporteur.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hr">ako su plombe tijekom aktivnosti prijevoza oštećene ili neovlašteno izmijenjene u okolnostima koje su izvan kontrole prijevoznika;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hu">a szállítási művelet során a zárak a fuvarozón kívül álló okok miatt feltört állapotba kerülnek vagy illetéktelen beavatkozást szenvednek;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="it">in caso di rottura o manomissione dei sigilli durante il trasporto per cause indipendenti dalla volontà del trasportatore;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lt">Vykdant transporto operaciją dėl nuo vežėjo nepriklausančių priežasčių plombos pažeidžiamos arba bandomos nuimti.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lv">Pārvadājuma operācijas laikā ir bojāta plomba vai ar to ir veiktas manipulācijas tādu iemeslu dēļ, kuri ir ārpus pārvadātāja kontroles</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="me">Plombe su slomljene ili oštećene tokom transportne operacije iz razloga koji su van kontrole prevoznika.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="mt">is-siġilli jinfetħu jew jiġu mbagħbsa waqt it-trasport, minħabba kawżi li m’għandux kontroll fuqhom it-trasportatur;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="nl">de verzegelingen zijn verbroken of gemanipuleerd tijdens het douanevervoer door een oorzaak buiten de wil van de vervoerder;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pl">Zamknięcia zostały zdjęte albo naruszone w trakcie operacji transportowej z przyczyn niezależnych od przewoźnika.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pt">Os selos estão quebrados ou apresentam sinais de manipulação abusiva no decurso de uma operação de transporte por razões alheias à vontade do transportador;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="ro">sigiliile sunt rupte sau au fost supuse unei manipulări frauduloase în cursul operațiunii de transport din motive independente de voința transportatorului;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sk">Počas prepravy došlo k poškodeniu uzáver alebo neoprávnenej manipulácii s nimi z dôvodov, ktoré sú mimo kontroly dopravcu.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sl">so bile med prevozno operacijo carinske oznake poškodovane ali spremenjene brez dovoljenja iz razlogov, na katere prevoznik ni mogel vplivati;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sr">Plombe su polomljene ili neovlašćeno izmenjene u toku tranzitnog postupka iz razloga koji nisu pod kontrolom prevoznika</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sv">Förseglingar bryts eller manipuleras i samband med transporten på grund av omständigheter som ligger utanför fraktförarens kontroll.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="uk">Пломби порушені або підроблено під час транспортного перевезення з причин, які не залежать від перевізника.</ns7:description>
            </ns4:LsdList>
         </ns3:RDEntry>
         <ns3:RDEntry>
            <ns4:RDEntryStatus>
               <ns5:state>valid</ns5:state>
               <ns5:activeFrom>2025-11-01</ns5:activeFrom>
            </ns4:RDEntryStatus>
            <ns4:dataItem name="Code">3</ns4:dataItem>
            <ns4:LsdList>
               <ns7:description lang="bg">стоките са прехвърлени от едно транспортно средство на друго транспортно средство под надзора на митническия орган;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="cs">zboží je pod dohledem celního orgánu přeloženo z jednoho dopravního prostředku na jiný dopravní prostředek;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="da">varer under toldmyndighedens tilsyn omlades fra ét transportmiddel til et andet transportmiddel</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="de">Waren unter zollamtlicher Überwachung von einem Beförderungsmittel auf ein anderes umgeladen werden;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="el">όταν, υπό την επιτήρηση της τελωνειακής αρχής, τα εμπορεύματα μεταφορτώνονται από ένα μεταφορικό μέσο σε άλλο·</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="en">Under the supervision of the customs authority, goods are transferred from one means of transport to another means of transport.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="es">cuando, bajo la vigilancia de la autoridad aduanera, las mercancías se trasladen de un medio de transporte a otro;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="et">Tolli järelevalve all laaditakse kaup ühelt transpordivahendilt ümber teisele transpordivahendile.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fi">tavarat uudelleenlastataan tulliviranomaisen valvonnassa toiseen kulkuneuvoon;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fr">Sous la surveillance de l’autorité douanière, les marchandises sont transférées d’un moyen de transport à un autre moyen de transport.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hr">ako se roba, pod nadzorom carinskog tijela, pretovaruje s jednog prijevoznog sredstva na drugo;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hu">az árukat egy szállítóeszközről a vámhatóság felügyelete mellett átrakodják egy másik szállítóeszközre;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="it">se, sotto il controllo dell’autorità doganale, le merci sono trasferite da un mezzo di trasporto a un altro;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lt">Prekės, prižiūrint muitinei, perkraunamos iš vienos transporto priemonės į kitą transporto priemonę.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lv">Muitas dienesta uzraudzībā preces tiek pārceltas no viena transportlīdzekļa uz citu transportlīdzekli</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="me">Pod nadzorom carinskog organa, roba se prenosi sa jednog prevoznog sredstva na drugo.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="mt">taħt is-superviżjoni tal-awtorità doganali, il-merkanzija tiġi trasferita minn mezz ta’ trasport għal ieħor;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="nl">goederen onder toezicht van de douaneautoriteit van het ene vervoermiddel in of op het andere vervoermiddel zijn overgeladen;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pl">Towary zostały przeładowane z jednego środka transportu na drugi, pod dozorem celnym.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pt">Sob a supervisão da autoridade aduaneira, as mercadorias são transferidas de um meio de transporte para outro meio de transporte;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="ro">sub supravegherea autorității vamale, mărfurile sunt transferate dintr-un mijloc de transport în alt mijloc de transport;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sk">Tovar sa pod dohľadom colného orgánu preložil z jedného dopravného prostriedku na iný dopravný prostriedok.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sl">se pod nadzorom carinskih organov blago prenese z enega prevoznega sredstva na drugo prevozno sredstvo;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sr">Roba se pretovara sa jednog prevoznog sredstva na drugo prevozno sredstvo pod nadzorom carinskog organa</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sv">Varorna omlastas under övervakning av tullmyndigheten från ett transportmedel till ett annat.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="uk">Під наглядом митного органу товари перевантажені з одного транспортного засобу на інший.</ns7:description>
            </ns4:LsdList>
         </ns3:RDEntry>
         <ns3:RDEntry>
            <ns4:RDEntryStatus>
               <ns5:state>valid</ns5:state>
               <ns5:activeFrom>2025-11-01</ns5:activeFrom>
            </ns4:RDEntryStatus>
            <ns4:dataItem name="Code">4</ns4:dataItem>
            <ns4:LsdList>
               <ns7:description lang="bg">съществува неизбежна опасност, налагаща незабавно частично или пълно разтоварване на пломбираното транспортно средство;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="cs">bezprostředně hrozící nebezpečí vyžaduje okamžitou částečnou nebo úplnou vykládku dopravního prostředku opatřeného celní závěrou;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="da">en overhængende fare nødvendiggør, at de forseglede transportmidler straks losses helt eller delvis</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="de">eine unmittelbar drohende Gefahr ein sofortiges teilweises oder vollständiges Entladen des verschlossenen Beförderungsmittels erfordert;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="el">σε περίπτωση επικείμενου κινδύνου που απαιτεί την άμεση, μερική ή ολική, εκφόρτωση από το σφραγισμένο μεταφορικό μέσο·</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="en">Imminent danger necessitates immediate partial or total unloading of the sealed means of transport.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="es">cuando exista un peligro inminente que exija la descarga inmediata, parcial o total, del medio de transporte precintado;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="et">Otsese ohu tõttu on vaja osaliselt või täielikult ümber laadida transpordivahend, millele on paigaldatud tollitõkend.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fi">välittömästi uhkaavan vaaran vuoksi on välttämätöntä viipymättä purkaa tavarat osittain tai kokonaan sinetöidystä kulkuneuvosta;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fr">Un péril imminent nécessite le déchargement immédiat, partiel ou total, du moyen de transport scellé.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hr">ako je zbog neposredne opasnosti nužno odmah djelomično ili potpuno istovariti prijevozno sredstvo pod plombom;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hu">fenyegető veszély miatt a zárral ellátott szállítóeszközből azonnal, részlegesen vagy teljesen ki kell rakodni;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="it">in caso di pericolo imminente che renda necessario l’immediato scarico, parziale o totale, del mezzo di trasporto sigillato;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lt">Gresiant neišvengiamam pavojui būtina nedelsiant iškrauti visą užplombuotos transporto priemonės krovinį arba jo dalį.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lv">Draud nenovēršamas briesmas, tāpēc nekavējoties ir pilnībā vai daļēji jāizkrauj transportlīdzeklis, kuram ir uzlikta plomba</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="me">Neposredna opasnost zahtijeva trenutno djelimično ili potpuno istovaranje plombiranog prevoznog sredstva.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="mt">minħabba periklu imminenti ikun meħtieġ li jinħatt parzjalment jew totalment b’mod immedjat il-mezz tat-trasport issiġillat;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="nl">het verzegelde vervoermiddel door dreigend gevaar onmiddellijk gedeeltelijk of geheel gelost moet worden;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pl">Bezpośrednie niebezpieczeństwo wymusza niezwłoczny częściowy lub całkowity rozładunek z zaplombowanego środka transportu.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pt">Um perigo iminente requer a descarga imediata, no todo ou em parte, do meio de transporte selado;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="ro">pericolele iminente necesită descărcarea parțială sau totală imediată din mijlocul de transport sigilat;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sk">Z dôvodu bezprostredného nebezpečenstva je nevyhnuté uzáverou označený dopravný prostriedok okamžite čiastočne alebo úplne vyložiť.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sl">je treba nemudoma zaradi neposredne nevarnosti deloma ali v celoti raztovoriti prevozno sredstvo z nameščenimi carinskimi oznakami;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sr">Neposredna opasnost zahteva momentalni delimični ili potpuni istovar plombiranog prevoznog sredstva</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sv">En överhängande fara nödvändiggör omedelbar lossning av samtliga varor i det förseglade transportmedlet, eller av en del av dessa.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="uk">Безпосередня небезпека вимагає негайного часткового або повного розвантаження запломбованого транспортного засобу.</ns7:description>
            </ns4:LsdList>
         </ns3:RDEntry>
         <ns3:RDEntry>
            <ns4:RDEntryStatus>
               <ns5:state>valid</ns5:state>
               <ns5:activeFrom>2025-11-01</ns5:activeFrom>
            </ns4:RDEntryStatus>
            <ns4:dataItem name="Code">5</ns4:dataItem>
            <ns4:LsdList>
               <ns7:description lang="bg">има инцидент, който може да засегне способността на титуляря на режима или превозвача да изпълнява задълженията си;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="cs">dojde k události, která může ovlivnit schopnost držitele režimu nebo dopravce dostát svým závazkům;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="da">der opstår en hændelse med eventuel indvirkning på, om den person, der er ansvarlig for proceduren, eller operatøren kan opfylde sine forpligtelser</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="de">ein Ereignis vorliegt, dass die Fähigkeit des Inhabers des Verfahrens oder des Beförderers zur Einhaltung seiner Verpflichtungen beeinträchtigen könnte;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="el">σε περίπτωση συμβάντος που ενδέχεται να επηρεάσει την τήρηση των υποχρεώσεων του δικαιούχου του καθεστώτος ή του μεταφορέα·</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="en">There is an incident which may affect the ability of the Holder of the procedure or the carrier to comply with their obligations.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="es">cuando se produzca una incidencia que pueda afectar a la capacidad del titular del régimen o del transportista de cumplir sus obligaciones;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="et">Esineb vahejuhtum, mis võib mõjutada protseduuri pidaja või vedaja võimet oma kohustusi täita.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fi">on sattunut tapahtuma, joka voi vaikuttaa menettelynhaltijan tai liikenteenharjoittajaan valmiuteen noudattaa velvoitteitaan;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fr">Un incident se produit, qui est susceptible de compromettre la capacité du titulaire du régime ou du transporteur à s’acquitter de ses obligations.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hr">ako je došlo do nezgode koja može utjecati na sposobnost korisnika postupka ili prijevoznika da ispune svoje obveze;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hu">olyan esemény következik be, amely befolyásolhatja a vámeljárás jogosultjának vagy a fuvarozónak azon képességét, hogy teljesítse kötelezettségeit;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="it">se si verifica un incidente che può condizionare la capacità del titolare del regime o del trasportatore di adempiere ai propri obblighi;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lt">Įvyksta incidentas, galintis padaryti poveikį procedūros vykdytojo arba vežėjo gebėjimui vykdyti savo pareigas.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lv">Noticis starpgadījums, kas var ietekmēt procedūras izmantotāja vai pārvadātāja spēju izpildīt savus pienākumus</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="me">Došlo je do incidenta koji može uticati na sposobnost nosioca postupka ili prevoznika da ispuni svoje obaveze.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="mt">ikun hemm inċident li jista’ jaffettwa l-ħila tad-detentur tal-proċedura jew li t-trasportatur ikun jista’ jikkonforma mal-obbligi tiegħu;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="nl">zich een voorval heeft voorgedaan dat tot gevolg kan hebben dat de houder van de regeling of de vervoerder niet langer aan zijn verplichtingen kan voldoen;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pl">Ma miejsce zdarzenie, które może mieć wpływ na zdolność korzystającego z procedury lub przewoźnika do dopełnienia swoich obowiązków.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pt">Se verifique um incidente que pode afetar a capacidade do titular do regime ou do transportador para cumprir as suas obrigações;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="ro">survine un incident care poate afecta capacitatea titularului regimului sau a transportatorului de a-și îndeplini obligațiile;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sk">Došlo k udalosti, ktorá môže postihnúť schopnosť držiteľa colného režimu alebo dopravcu splniť si povinnosti.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sl">se je zgodil izredni dogodek, ki bi lahko vplival na sposobnost imetnika postopka ali prevoznika, da izpolni svoje obveznosti;</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sr">Došlo je do incidenta koji može uticati na sposobnost nosioca postupka ili prevoznika da ispuni svoje obaveze</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sv">En händelse inträffar som kan påverka förmågan hos den person som är ansvarig för förfarandet eller hos fraktföraren att fullgöra sina skyldigheter.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="uk">Стався інцидент, який може вплинути на здатність Суб'єкта процедури або перевізника виконувати свої зобов’язання.</ns7:description>
            </ns4:LsdList>
         </ns3:RDEntry>
         <ns3:RDEntry>
            <ns4:RDEntryStatus>
               <ns5:state>valid</ns5:state>
               <ns5:activeFrom>2025-11-01</ns5:activeFrom>
            </ns4:RDEntryStatus>
            <ns4:dataItem name="Code">6</ns4:dataItem>
            <ns4:LsdList>
               <ns7:description lang="bg">променена е някоя от съставните части на едно транспортно средство по смисъла на член 296, параграф 2 от настоящия регламент.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="cs">dojde ke změně kteréhokoli z prvků tvořících jediný dopravní prostředek uvedený v čl. 296 odst. 2 tohoto nařízení.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="da">et af de elementer, der indgår i et og samme transportmiddel som omhandlet i denne forordnings artikel 296, stk. 2, ændres.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="de">eines der Elemente, die ein einziges Beförderungsmittel gemäß Artikel 296 Absatz 2 darstellen, ausgetauscht wird.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="el">σε περίπτωση αλλαγής οποιουδήποτε από τα στοιχεία που αποτελούν ενιαίο μεταφορικό μέσο, όπως αναφέρεται στο άρθρο 296 παράγραφος 2 του παρόντος κανονισμού.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="en">Any of the elements constituting a single means of transport as referred to in Article 296(2) UCC/IA is changed.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="es">cuando se modifique alguno de los elementos constitutivos de un medio de transporte único a que se refiere el artículo 296, apartado 2, del presente Reglamento.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="et">Vahetatakse välja mis tahes osa transpordivahendist, mida käsitatakse ühe transpordivahendina, nagu on osutatud RA artikli 296 lõikes 2.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fi">jokin tämän asetuksen 296 artiklan 2 kohdassa tarkoitetun yhden kulkuneuvon muodostavista osatekijöistä muuttuu.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fr">un des éléments constituant un moyen de transport unique visé à l’article 296, paragraphe 2, du présent règlement a été modifié.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hr">ako se zamijeni bilo koji element koji čini jedno prijevozno sredstvo iz članka 296. stavka 2. ove Uredbe.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hu">az e rendelet 296. cikkének (2) bekezdésében említettek szerinti egyetlen szállítóeszközt alkotó elemek bármelyikét lecserélik.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="it">se uno degli elementi che costituiscono un mezzo di trasporto unico ai sensi dell’articolo 296, paragrafo 2, del presente regolamento è modificato.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lt">Pakeičiamas bet kuris elementas, sudarantis Komisijos įgyvendinimo reglamento (ES) 2015/2447 296 straipsnio 2 dalyje nurodytą vieną transporto priemonę.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lv">Mainījies kāds no elementiem, kas veido vienu transportlīdzekli, kā minēts šīs regulas 296. panta 2. punktā</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="me">Bilo koji od elemenata koji čine jedinstveno prevozno sredstvo, kako je navedeno u članu 296(2) UCC/IA, je promijenjen.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="mt">jinbidel kwalunkwe wieħed mill-elementi li jikkostitwixxi mezz uniku ta’ trasport kif imsemmi fl-Artikolu 296(2) ta’ dan ir-Regolament.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="nl">een van de onderdelen van een samenstel van vervoermiddelen dat als één vervoermiddel wordt beschouwd zoals bedoeld in artikel 296, lid 2, van deze verordening, is gewijzigd.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pl">Którykolwiek z elementów stanowiących pojedyńczy środek transportu, zgodnie z art. 296(2) UKC/RW, zostaje zmieniony.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pt">Qualquer um dos elementos que constituem um meio de transporte único, tal como referido no artigo 296.o, n.o 2, do presente regulamento, foi alterado.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="ro">oricare dintre elementele care constituie un mijloc de transport unic, menționate la articolul 296 alineatul (2) din prezentul regulament, este schimbat.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sk">Došlo k zmene ktoréhokoľvek z prvkov tvoriacich jeden dopravný prostriedok uvedený v článku 296 ods. 2 VNCKÚ 2015/2447 .</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sl">se spremeni kateri koli od elementov, ki sestavljajo eno prevozno sredstvo iz člena 296(2) te uredbe.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sr">Bilo koji od elemenata koji čine jedno prevozno sredstvo kako je navedeno u članu 296. (2) UCC/IA (član 3IncidentCode. stav 3.) se menja</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sv">Någon av de delar som utgör ett enda transportmedel enligt artikel 296.2 i denna förordning har ändrats.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="uk">Змінюється будь-який з елементів, що становлять один транспортний засіб, як зазначено в статті 296(2) UCC/IA.</ns7:description>
            </ns4:LsdList>
         </ns3:RDEntry>
         <ns3:RDEntry>
            <ns4:RDEntryStatus>
               <ns5:state>valid</ns5:state>
               <ns5:activeFrom>2025-12-02</ns5:activeFrom>
            </ns4:RDEntryStatus>
            <ns4:dataItem name="Code">7</ns4:dataItem>
            <ns4:LsdList>
               <ns7:description lang="en">Seals were replaced, added or removed by the customs authorities.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fr">Les scellés ont été remplacés, ajoutés ou enlevés par les autorités douanières.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hu">A vámhatóság a vámzárat kicserélte, hozzáadta vagy eltávolította.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lt">Muitinė pakeitė, uždėjo arba nuėmė plombas.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lv">Plombas ir nomainītas, uzliktas vai noņemtas muitas iestādē</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="me">Plombe su zamijenjene, dodate ili uklonjene od strane carinskih organa.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pl">Zamknięcia zostały zmienione, nałożone lub zdjęte przez organ celny</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sk">Uzávery boli zmenené, pridané alebo odstránené colným orgánom.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sr">Plombe su zamenjene, dodate ili uklonjene od strane carinskog organa</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="uk">Пломби були замінені, додані або зняті митними органами</ns7:description>
            </ns4:LsdList>
         </ns3:RDEntry>
         <ns3:RDEntry>
            <ns4:RDEntryStatus>
               <ns5:state>valid</ns5:state>
               <ns5:activeFrom>2025-12-02</ns5:activeFrom>
            </ns4:RDEntryStatus>
            <ns4:dataItem name="Code">8</ns4:dataItem>
            <ns4:LsdList>
               <ns7:description lang="en">Without the supervision of the customs authority, goods were transferred from one means of transport to another means of transport, in accordance with Article 305(3) of UCC/IA.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="fr">Les marchandises ont été transférées d'un moyen de transport à un autre sans le contrôle des autorités douanières, conformément à l'article 305, paragraphe 3, du règlement d'exécution (UE) 2015/2447.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="hu">A vámhatóság felügyelete nélkül, az UVK/VA 305. cikkének (3) bekezdésével összhangban az árukat egyik szállítóeszközről egy másik szállítóeszközre átrakodták.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lt">Prekės, muitinei neprižiūrint, perkraunamos iš vienos transporto priemonės į kitą transporto priemonę, vadovaujantis Komisijos įgyvendinimo reglamento (ES) 2015/2447 305 straipsnio 3 dalimi</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="lv">Preces tika pārkrautas citā transporta līdzeklī bez muitas uzraudzības saskaņā ar Komisijas īstenošanas regulas 2015/2447 305. panta 3. punktu.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="me">Bez nadzora carinskog organa, roba je prenesena sa jednog prevoznog sredstva na drugo, u skladu sa članom 305(3) UCC/IA.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="pl">Bez dozoru organu celnego towary zostały przeładowane z jednego środka transportu na drugi, zgodnie z art. 305 ust. 3 UKC/RW</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sk">Tovar bol preložený z jedného dopravného prostriedku na iný dopravný prostriedok bez dohľadu colného orgánu v súlade s článkom 305 ods. 3 VNCKÚ 2015/2447.</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="sr">Roba je pretovarena sa jednog prevoznog sredstva na drugo, bez carinskog nadzora, u skladu sa članom 305 stav3. UCC/IA</ns7:description>
               <ns7:description lang="uk">Товари були перевантажені з одного транспотного засобу на інший транспортний засіб без нагляду митного органу відповідно до статті 305(3) UCC/IA</ns7:description>
            </ns4:LsdList>
         </ns3:RDEntry>
      </ns2:RDEntity>
   </ns0:RDEntityList>
</ns8:ExtractValidReferenceDataRespMsg>
